## MONICA KAY PROVENCE

• Full-Stack Software Developer •

I am a creative, detail-oriented person with a passion for intuitive, user-focused design. After almost a decade working as an Art Educator, Creative Entrepreneur, and Healthcare Advocate, I became interested in software development. I enrolled in a self-guided Python course through Udemy, and quickly realized that software development was the perfect combination of creative and strategic problem solving.

**©** 615-656-3541

### EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full-Stack Development 2021

Coursera JavaScript Animation 2020 for Websites, Data Visualization, and Games

2020 CSS Animated Components with ReactJS

Udemy 2020 UX Design: User Behavior & Psychology

Python Bootcamp 2019

> Middle Tennessee State University B.S. Art Education

# TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### Nashville Software School

Full-Stack Software Developer

Fully Remote

Intensive six-month, full-time software development bootcamp with immersive, lab-based learning in Full-Stack Development, with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, SQL, and Python.

- Simulated work-based learning environment
- Virtual work environment
- Emphasis on team-based development
- Experience with Scrum process and agile workflow
- Used Git & GitHub for version control
- Experience in a full-time remote environment

### Languages & Technologies

- HTML 5, CSS3, JavaScript, React JS, JSON Server, SQL & Python
- · Git & GitHub
- Visual Studio & Visual Studio Code
- Sketchboard, Miro, Figma & dbdiabram
- Canva, Vectornator, Concepts, & Bazaart

### COMMUNITY

2016

Nashville JavaScript Attend monthly meetups and actively participate in group discussions.

Code For Nashville

Attend monthly meetups and actively collaborate with other developers to solve social issues through innovative development.

PyNash

Attend monthly meetups and actively participate in group discussions.

Women In Technology of Tennessee

Attend monthly meetups and actively participate in group discussions.

freeCodeCamp

Attend weekly meetups to practice algorithms and data-structure coding skills with other developers.

### PROJECTS

#### Wide Retriever

Client-Side Capstone

cutt.ly/retriever (7)

Dashboard application built with React JS where dog owners can set exercise and training goals for their dogs and track their progress.

- Full CRUD functionality for many-to-many data relationships
- Utilized Miro and dbdiagram for planning
- Implemented JSON Server to store and return data
- Used CSS, Vectornator, and Canva for design

#### **Nutshell: Lawn Artists**

cutt.ly/nutshell (7)

Social Application

User-focused application built 100% remotely by a team of four.

- Actively participated in project planning, Scrum, and MVP Integrity.
- Implemented full CRUD functionality on the Articles section.
- Pair programmed the Weather component using OpenWeather API.
- Utilized mock user authentication and session storage

### Truncheons & Flagons

cutt.ly/truncheons

Score-Keeping Application

Companion application for a medieval drinking game, built 100% remotely by a team of five.

- Implemented real-time form validation.
- Maintained MVP Integrity.
- Maintained component and application state

### SKILLS

Interpersonal Skills
Time Management
Public Speaking
Team Building
Remote Work
Conflict Resolution
Project Planning

### INTERESTS

Performing Improv Comedy
Directing Sketch Comedy
Writing Haikus
International Travel
Experimental Mixology
Painting Oil Portraits
Reading
Walking My Dog

### AWARDS

"The Orator"

Nashville Software School For being able to cheer up my teammates and resolve conflicts smoothly,

"The Tomb Raider"
Nashville Software School
For digging up as much
documentation as possible on
new technologies.

"The Burrito" Nashville Software School For being a positive force in the Cohort.

"Continuing Education Award"

Kemberton

For outstanding work in account resolution after only two months on the job.

### EXPERIENCE

#### Kemberton

Denials Specialist

Franklin, TN 2017 - 2020

Healthcare Company specializing in Patient and Provider advocacy through complex claims resolution.

- Wrote legal appeals on behalf of healthcare Providers & Patients.
- Played key role in resolving all high-dollar, complex accounts.
- Identified repetitive tasks, and wrote macros to automate them.
- Minimized opportunities for human error by building and distributing appeal templates to my teammates.
- Conducted daily research on current insurance policies..

### Technologies Used

- Teams, Office 360, OneNote, Planner, Access, Excel, Word
- EPIC Systems

#### **Paint Nite**

Nashville, TN & Memphis, TN 2014 - 2019

Licensee/Artist

The premier "social painting" company in the U.S.

- Started as a Teaching Artist and took over operations for the Nashville Market in 2017.
- Grew Private Event revenue for the Nashville Market from roughly \$10,000 annually to over \$70,000 in my first year.
- Launched Paint Nite Memphis in 2018, and developed selfsustaining team remotely from home in Nashville, TN.

#### Technologies Used

- Facebook Ads, Hootsuite, Instagram Ads
- GSuite
- Canva, Photoshop, InDesign

### Firstlight Arts Academy

Art Teacher

Brentwood, TN 2013 - 2016

Artist training studio for students age four to adult.

- Contributed to comprehensive curricula for all ages.
- Identified individual student's learning needs and modified teaching style accordingly.

### VOLUNTEER

#### Disaster Relief

Tornado Relief Coordinator

Nashville, TN March 2020

- Worked closely with Hands On Nashville to dispatch teams to locations where volunteers were needed.
- Assisted with manual labor and cleanup.

Covid-19 Essentials Distributer

April - July 2020

• Packaged and delivered essential products to elderly and immunocompromised Nashville Residents during pandemic.

#### Kids Arts Festival

Franklin, TN 2015 - 2016

Volunteer Event Coordinator

Coordinated execution of a community mural, painted by

- hundreds of participants during the festival.Oversaw activities of volunteers and art booths on site.
- Curated student art gallery with over 500 works of art.